\*protected email\*



MENUMENU



Privacy Policy
==============

What data we collect and how we use it.

Table of Contents

Toggle

        * [Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e., the “controller”)?](#Who_is_the_responsible_party_for_the_recording_of_data_on_this_website_ie_the_%E2%80%9Ccontroller%E2%80%9D "Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e., the “controller”)?")
        * [What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?](#What_rights_do_you_have_as_far_as_your_information_is_concerned "What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?")
* [2\. Hosting and Content Delivery Networks (CDN)](#2_Hosting_and_Content_Delivery_Networks_CDN "2. Hosting and Content Delivery Networks (CDN)")
    * [Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)](#Information_about_the_responsible_party_referred_to_as_the_%E2%80%9Ccontroller%E2%80%9D_in_the_GDPR "Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)")
    * [General information on the legal basis for the data processing on this website](#General_information_on_the_legal_basis_for_the_data_processing_on_this_website "General information on the legal basis for the data processing on this website")
    * [Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)](#Right_to_object_to_the_collection_of_data_in_special_cases_right_to_object_to_direct_advertising_Art_21_GDPR "Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)")
    * [Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency](#Right_to_log_a_complaint_with_the_competent_supervisory_agency "Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency")
    * [Umami Analytics (self-hosted)](#Umami_Analytics_self-hosted "Umami Analytics (self-hosted)")
* [8\. Online-based Audio and Video Conferences (Conference tools)](#8_Online-based_Audio_and_Video_Conferences_Conference_tools "8. Online-based Audio and Video Conferences (Conference tools)")

Privacy Policy
==============

### **1\. An overview of data protection**

#### **General information**

The following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview of what will happen with your personal data when you visit this website. The term “personal data” comprises all data that can be used to personally identify you. For detailed information about the subject matter of data protection, please consult our Data Protection Declaration, which we have included beneath this copy.

#### **Data recording on this website**

##### **Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e., the “controller”)?**

The data on this website is processed by the operator of the website, whose contact information is available under section “Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)” in this Privacy Policy.

#### **How do we record your data?**

We collect your data as a result of your sharing of your data with us. This may, for instance be information you enter into our contact form.

Other data shall be recorded by our IT systems automatically or after you consent to its recording during your website visit. This data comprises primarily technical information (e.g., web browser, operating system, or time the site was accessed). This information is recorded automatically when you access this website.

##### **What are the purposes we use your data for?**

A portion of the information is generated to guarantee the error free provision of the website. Other data may be used to analyze your user patterns.

##### **What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?**

You have the right to receive information about the source, recipients, and purposes of your archived personal data at any time without having to pay a fee for such disclosures. You also have the right to demand that your data are rectified or eradicated. If you have consented to data processing, you have the option to revoke this consent at any time, which shall affect all future data processing. Moreover, you have the right to demand that the processing of your data be restricted under certain circumstances. Furthermore, you have the right to log a complaint with the competent supervising agency.

Please do not hesitate to contact us at any time if you have questions about this or any other data protection related issues.

#### **Analysis tools and tools provided by third parties**

There is a possibility that your browsing patterns will be statistically analyzed when your visit this website. Such analyses are performed primarily with what we refer to as analysis programs.

For detailed information about these analysis programs please consult our Data Protection Declaration below.

### **2\. Hosting and Content Delivery Networks (CDN)**

We are hosting the content of our website at the following provider:

#### **Hetzner**

The provider is the Hetzner Online GmbH, Industriestr. 25, 91710 Gunzenhausen, Germany (hereinafter referred to as Hetzner).

For details, please view the data privacy policy of Hetzner: [https://www.hetzner.com/de/rechtliches/datenschutz](https://www.hetzner.com/de/rechtliches/datenschutz).

We use Hetzner on the basis of Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in the most reliable depiction of our website possible. If appropriate consent has been obtained, the processing is carried out exclusively on the basis of Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 (1) TDDDG, insofar the consent includes the storage of cookies or the access to information in the user’s end device (e.g., device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TDDDG. This consent can be revoked at any time.

**Data processing**

We have concluded a data processing agreement (DPA) for the use of the above-mentioned service. This is a contract mandated by data privacy laws that guarantees that they process personal data of our website visitors only based on our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

#### **Cloudflare**

We use the “Cloudflare” service provided by Cloudflare Inc., 101 Townsend St., San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. (hereinafter referred to as “Cloudflare”).

Cloudflare offers a content delivery network with DNS that is available worldwide. As a result, the information transfer that occurs between your browser and our website is technically routed via Cloudflare’s network. This enables Cloudflare to analyze data transactions between your browser and our website and to work as a filter between our servers and potentially malicious data traffic from the Internet. In this context, Cloudflare may also use cookies or other technologies deployed to recognize Internet users, which shall, however, only be used for the herein described purpose.

The use of Cloudflare is based on our legitimate interest in a provision of our website offerings that is as error free and secure as possible (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR).

Data transmission to the US is based on the Standard Contractual Clauses (SCC) of the European Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

For more information on Cloudflare’s security precautions and data privacy policies, please follow this link: [https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

The company is certified in accordance with the “EU-US Data Privacy Framework” (DPF). The DPF is an agreement between the European Union and the US, which is intended to ensure compliance with European data protection standards for data processing in the US. Every company certified under the DPF is obliged to comply with these data protection standards. For more information, please contact the provider under the following link: [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active)

**Data processing**

We have concluded a data processing agreement (DPA) for the use of the above-mentioned service. This is a contract mandated by data privacy laws that guarantees that they process personal data of our website visitors only based on our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

### **3\. General information and mandatory information**

#### **Data protection**

The operators of this website and its pages take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Hence, we handle your personal data as confidential information and in compliance with the statutory data protection regulations and this Data Protection Declaration.

Whenever you use this website, a variety of personal information will be collected. Personal data comprises data that can be used to personally identify you. This Data Protection Declaration explains which data we collect as well as the purposes we use this data for. It also explains how, and for which purpose the information is collected.

We herewith advise you that the transmission of data via the Internet (i.e., through e-mail communications) may be prone to security gaps. It is not possible to completely protect data against third-party access.

#### **Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)**

The data processing controller on this website is:

David Luna  
Gartenstr. 26  
10115 Berlin

Phone:

\*protected email\*

E-Mail:

\*protected email\*

(please use our [contact form](https://www.gammabeyond.com/en/contact/))

The controller is the natural person or legal entity that single-handedly or jointly with others makes decisions as to the purposes of and resources for the processing of personal data (e.g., names, e-mail addresses, etc.).

#### **Storage duration**

Unless a more specific storage period has been specified in this privacy policy, your personal data will remain with us until the purpose for which it was collected no longer applies. If you assert a justified request for deletion or revoke your consent to data processing, your data will be deleted, unless we have other legally permissible reasons for storing your personal data (e.g., tax or commercial law retention periods); in the latter case, the deletion will take place after these reasons cease to apply.

#### **General information on the legal basis for the data processing on this website**

If you have consented to data processing, we process your personal data on the basis of Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR or Art. 9 (2)(a) GDPR, if special categories of data are processed according to Art. 9 (1) DSGVO. In the case of explicit consent to the transfer of personal data to third countries, the data processing is also based on Art. 49 (1)(a) GDPR. If you have consented to the storage of cookies or to the access to information in your end device (e.g., via device fingerprinting), the data processing is additionally based on § 25 (1) TDDDG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If your data is required for the fulfillment of a contract or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures, we process your data on the basis of Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR. Furthermore, if your data is required for the fulfillment of a legal obligation, we process it on the basis of Art. 6(1)(c) GDPR. Furthermore, the data processing may be carried out on the basis of our legitimate interest according to Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Information on the relevant legal basis in each individual case is provided in the following paragraphs of this privacy policy.

#### **Recipients of personal data**

In the scope of our business activities, we cooperate with various external parties. In some cases, this also requires the transfer of personal data to these external parties. We only disclose personal data to external parties if this is required as part of the fulfillment of a contract, if we are legally obligated to do so (e.g., disclosure of data to tax authorities), if we have a legitimate interest in the disclosure pursuant to Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR, or if another legal basis permits the disclosure of this data. When using processors, we only disclose personal data of our customers on the basis of a valid contract on data processing. In the case of joint processing, a joint processing agreement is concluded.

#### **Revocation of your consent to the processing of data**

A wide range of data processing transactions are possible only subject to your express consent. You can also revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.

#### **Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)**

IN THE EVENT THAT DATA ARE PROCESSED ON THE BASIS OF ART. 6(1)(E) OR (F) GDPR, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO AT ANY TIME OBJECT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA BASED ON GROUNDS ARISING FROM YOUR UNIQUE SITUATION. THIS ALSO APPLIES TO ANY PROFILING BASED ON THESE PROVISIONS. TO DETERMINE THE LEGAL BASIS, ON WHICH ANY PROCESSING OF DATA IS BASED, PLEASE CONSULT THIS DATA PROTECTION DECLARATION. IF YOU LOG AN OBJECTION, WE WILL NO LONGER PROCESS YOUR AFFECTED PERSONAL DATA, UNLESS WE ARE IN A POSITION TO PRESENT COMPELLING PROTECTION WORTHY GROUNDS FOR THE PROCESSING OF YOUR DATA, THAT OUTWEIGH YOUR INTERESTS, RIGHTS AND FREEDOMS OR IF THE PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING IS THE CLAIMING, EXERCISING OR DEFENCE OF LEGAL ENTITLEMENTS (OBJECTION PURSUANT TO ART. 21(1) GDPR).

IF YOUR PERSONAL DATA IS BEING PROCESSED IN ORDER TO ENGAGE IN DIRECT ADVERTISING, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO OBJECT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR AFFECTED PERSONAL DATA FOR THE PURPOSES OF SUCH ADVERTISING AT ANY TIME. THIS ALSO APPLIES TO PROFILING TO THE EXTENT THAT IT IS AFFILIATED WITH SUCH DIRECT ADVERTISING. IF YOU OBJECT, YOUR PERSONAL DATA WILL SUBSEQUENTLY NO LONGER BE USED FOR DIRECT ADVERTISING PURPOSES (OBJECTION PURSUANT TO ART. 21(2) GDPR).

#### **Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency**

In the event of violations of the GDPR, data subjects are entitled to log a complaint with a supervisory agency, in particular in the member state where they usually maintain their domicile, place of work or at the place where the alleged violation occurred. The right to log a complaint is in effect regardless of any other administrative or court proceedings available as legal resources.

#### **Right to data portability**

You have the right to have data that we process automatically on the basis of your consent or in fulfillment of a contract handed over to you or to a third party in a common, machine-readable format. If you should demand the direct transfer of the data to another controller, this will be done only if it is technically feasible.

#### **SSL or TLS encryption**

For security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content, such as orders or requests that you send to us as the site operator, this site uses SSL or TLS encryption. You can recognize an encrypted connection by the fact that the address line of the browser changes from "http://" to "https://" and by the lock symbol in your browser line. If SSL or TLS encryption is activated, the data you transmit to us cannot be read by third parties.

#### **Information about, rectification and eradication of data**

Within the scope of the applicable statutory provisions, you have the right to demand information about your archived personal data, their source and recipients as well as the purpose of the processing of your data at any time. You may also have a right to have your data rectified or eradicated. If you have questions about this subject matter or any other questions about personal data, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time.

#### **Right to demand processing restrictions**

You have the right to demand the imposition of restrictions as far as the processing of your personal data is concerned. To do so, you may contact us at any time. The right to demand restriction of processing applies in the following cases:

* In the event that you should dispute the correctness of your data archived by us, we will usually need some time to verify this claim. During the time that this investigation is ongoing, you have the right to demand that we restrict the processing of your personal data.
* If the processing of your personal data was/is conducted in an unlawful manner, you have the option to demand the restriction of the processing of your data instead of demanding the eradication of this data.
* If we do not need your personal data any longer and you need it to exercise, defend or claim legal entitlements, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data instead of its eradication.
* If you have raised an objection pursuant to Art. 21(1) GDPR, your rights and our rights will have to be weighed against each other. As long as it has not been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to demand a restriction of the processing of your personal data.

If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data – with the exception of their archiving – may be processed only subject to your consent or to claim, exercise or defend legal entitlements or to protect the rights of other natural persons or legal entities or for important public interest reasons cited by the European Union or a member state of the EU.

### 4\. Recording of data on this website

#### **Cookies**

Our websites and pages use what the industry refers to as “cookies.” Cookies are small data packages that do not cause any damage to your device. They are either stored temporarily for the duration of a session (session cookies) or they are permanently archived on your device (permanent cookies). Session cookies are automatically deleted once you terminate your visit. Permanent cookies remain archived on your device until you actively delete them, or they are automatically eradicated by your web browser.

Cookies can be issued by us (first-party cookies) or by third-party companies (so-called third-party cookies). Third-party cookies enable the integration of certain services of third-party companies into websites (e.g., cookies for handling payment services).

Cookies have a variety of functions. Many cookies are technically essential since certain website functions would not work in the absence of these cookies (e.g., the shopping cart function or the display of videos). Other cookies may be used to analyze user behavior or for promotional purposes.

Cookies, which are required for the performance of electronic communication transactions, for the provision of certain functions you want to use (e.g., for the shopping cart function) or those that are necessary for the optimization (required cookies) of the website (e.g., cookies that provide measurable insights into the web audience), shall be stored on the basis of Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR, unless a different legal basis is cited. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the storage of required cookies to ensure the technically error-free and optimized provision of the operator’s services. If your consent to the storage of the cookies and similar recognition technologies has been requested, the processing occurs exclusively on the basis of the consent obtained (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 (1) TDDDG); this consent may be revoked at any time.

You have the option to set up your browser in such a manner that you will be notified any time cookies are placed and to permit the acceptance of cookies only in specific cases. You may also exclude the acceptance of cookies in certain cases or in general or activate the delete-function for the automatic eradication of cookies when the browser closes. If cookies are deactivated, the functions of this website may be limited.

Which cookies and services are used on this website can be found in this privacy policy.

#### **Technically necessary cookies**

These cookies do not require the consent of the user.

These cookies ensure functions without which you cannot use this website correctly. These cookies are used exclusively on this website and are therefore so-called first-party cookies. They are only stored on your computer during the current session. Technical cookies also include analytical cookies, which are used for access statistics, collect information in a general form and do not allow the identification of the visitor. This website uses technical cookies.

#### **Cookie via the plugin Polylang**

The "Polylang" plugin sets a cookie (pll\_language) to store which language has been selected on the website. In its default setting this cookie remains stored for 1 year. We have changed the cookie so that it is only stored as a session cookie and is therefore deleted after the session is ended (closing the tab).

#### **Server log files**

The provider of this website and its pages automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser communicates to us automatically. The information comprises:

* The type and version of browser used
* The used operating system
* Referrer URL
* The hostname of the accessing computer
* The time of the server inquiry
* The IP address

This data is not merged with other data sources.

This data is recorded on the basis of Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the technically error free depiction and the optimization of the operator’s website. In order to achieve this, server log files must be recorded.

#### **Contact form**

If you submit inquiries to us via our contact form, the information provided in the contact form as well as any contact information provided therein will be stored by us in order to handle your inquiry and in the event that we have further questions. We will not share this information without your consent.

The processing of these data is based on Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR, if your request is related to the execution of a contract or if it is necessary to carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases the processing is based on our legitimate interest in the effective processing of the requests addressed to us (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR) or on your agreement (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR) if this has been requested; the consent can be revoked at any time.

The information you have entered into the contact form shall remain with us until you ask us to eradicate the data, revoke your consent to the archiving of data or if the purpose for which the information is being archived no longer exists (e.g., after we have concluded our response to your inquiry). This shall be without prejudice to any mandatory legal provisions, in particular retention periods.

#### **Request by e-mail, telephone, or fax**

If you contact us by e-mail, telephone or fax, your request, including all resulting personal data (name, request) will be stored and processed by us for the purpose of processing your request. We do not pass these data on without your consent.

These data are processed on the basis of Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR if your inquiry is related to the fulfillment of a contract or is required for the performance of pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the data are processed on the basis of our legitimate interest in the effective handling of inquiries submitted to us (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR) or on the basis of your consent (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR) if it has been obtained; the consent can be revoked at any time.

The data sent by you to us via contact requests remain with us until you request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage lapses (e.g. after completion of your request). Mandatory statutory provisions - in particular statutory retention periods - remain unaffected.

### **5\. Analysis tools and advertising**

#### **Umami Analytics (self-hosted)**

We use a self-hosted instance of Umami Analytics on our website to analyze the reach of our website.

Umami allows us to analyze the behavior of our website visitors. For this purpose, the following data is collected: Page URL, HTTP request, HTTP referrer, browser, operating system, device type and IP address. The HTTP request and IP address are stored in a hash for 24 hours; within this period, a user can be recognized if he or she returns to the website. It is not possible to identify the person. Further information can be found in the documentation for Umami Analytics at: https://umami.is

There is:

* no personal data is collected
* no information such as cookies is stored in the browser
* no information is passed on, sent or sold to third parties
* no information is passed on to advertising companies
* we also host Umami Analytics on EU servers.

Insofar as consent has been obtained, the above service is used exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a DSGVO and § 25 TDDDG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If no consent has been obtained, the use of this service is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO; the website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing the user behavior of our website visitors as meaningfully as possible.

### **6\. Plug-ins and Tools**

#### **Acast**

For publishing podcasts we use the podcast hosting service Acast (Acast AB (publ), Kungsgatan 12, Stockholm 111 35, Sweden). The podcasts are thereby loaded by Acast or transmitted via Acast.

The legal basis for the use of the plug-ins is your consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a DSGVO. For information on how the respective social media providers process your personal data, please refer to their own privacy policy. In this respect, we are not the responsible party within the meaning of the DSGVO for the operation of the social media offerings.

Acast processes IP addresses and device information to enable podcast downloads/playbacks and to determine statistical data, such as call-up figures. This data is anonymized or pseudonymized before being stored in Acast's database, unless you are required to provide the podcasts.

The above data is transferred to Acast's servers in Sweden and processed there in order to verify the content of the distribution to the podcast's target audience and to make the podcast more interesting for the target audience.

For more information about how Acast handles user data, please see Acast's privacy policy here: https://www.acast.com/en/privacy

### **7\. Online marketing and partner programs**

#### **Affiliate Programs on this website**

We participate in affiliate partner programs. In conjunction with affiliate partner programs, ads of businesses (advertisers) are placed on websites of other enterprises within the affiliate partner network (publisher). If you click on one of these affiliate ads, you will be transferred to the promoted offer. If you should subsequently engage in a certain transaction (conversion), the publisher will receive a respective commission in exchange for the service. To be able to compute the commission amount, the affiliate network operator must be in a position to track the ad that has resulted in you seeing the offer and in you completing the predefined transaction. To make this possible, cookies or comparable recognition technologies are deployed (e.g., device fingerprinting).

Data is stored and analyzed on the basis of Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the correct computation of its affiliate compensation. If appropriate consent has been obtained, the processing is carried out exclusively on the basis of Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 (1) TDDDG, insofar the consent includes the storage of cookies or the access to information in the user’s end device (e.g., device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TDDDG. This consent can be revoked at any time.

We participate in the following affiliate programs:

#### **Amazon partner program**

The provider is Amazon Europe Core S.à.r.l. For details, please consult Amazon’s Data Privacy Declaration at: [https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010](https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010).

The company is certified in accordance with the “EU-US Data Privacy Framework” (DPF). The DPF is an agreement between the European Union and the US, which is intended to ensure compliance with European data protection standards for data processing in the US. Every company certified under the DPF is obliged to comply with these data protection standards. For more information, please contact the provider under the following link: [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt0000000TOWQAA4&status=Active](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt0000000TOWQAA4&status=Active)

### **8\. Online-based Audio and Video Conferences (Conference tools)**

#### **Data processing**

We use online conference tools, among other things, for communication with our customers. The tools we use are listed in detail below. If you communicate with us by video or audio conference using the Internet, your personal data will be collected and processed by the provider of the respective conference tool and by us. The conferencing tools collect all information that you provide/access to use the tools (email address and/or your phone number). Furthermore, the conference tools process the duration of the conference, start and end (time) of participation in the conference, number of participants and other “context information” related to the communication process (metadata).

Furthermore, the provider of the tool processes all the technical data required for the processing of the online communication. This includes, in particular, IP addresses, MAC addresses, device IDs, device type, operating system type and version, client version, camera type, microphone or loudspeaker and the type of connection.

Should content be exchanged, uploaded, or otherwise made available within the tool, it is also stored on the servers of the tool provider. Such content includes, but is not limited to, cloud recordings, chat/ instant messages, voicemail uploaded photos and videos, files, whiteboards, and other information shared while using the service.

Please note that we do not have complete influence on the data processing procedures of the tools used. Our possibilities are largely determined by the corporate policy of the respective provider. Further information on data processing by the conference tools can be found in the data protection declarations of the tools used, and which we have listed below this text.

#### **Purpose and legal bases**

The conference tools are used to communicate with prospective or existing contractual partners or to offer certain services to our customers (Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR). Furthermore, the use of the tools serves to generally simplify and accelerate communication with us or our company (legitimate interest in the meaning of Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR). Insofar as consent has been requested, the tools in question will be used on the basis of this consent; the consent may be revoked at any time with effect from that date.

#### **Duration of storage**

Data collected directly by us via the video and conference tools will be deleted from our systems immediately after you request us to delete it, revoke your consent to storage, or the reason for storing the data no longer applies. Stored cookies remain on your end device until you delete them. Mandatory legal retention periods remain unaffected.

We have no influence on the duration of storage of your data that is stored by the operators of the conference tools for their own purposes. For details, please directly contact the operators of the conference tools.

#### **Conference tools used**

We employ the following conference tools:

#### **Google Meet**

We use Google Meet. The provider is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. For details on data processing, please see the Google privacy policy: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

The company is certified in accordance with the “EU-US Data Privacy Framework” (DPF). The DPF is an agreement between the European Union and the US, which is intended to ensure compliance with European data protection standards for data processing in the US. Every company certified under the DPF is obliged to comply with these data protection standards. For more information, please contact the provider under the following link: [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?contact=true&id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)

**Data processing**

We have concluded a data processing agreement (DPA) for the use of the above-mentioned service. This is a contract mandated by data privacy laws that guarantees that they process personal data of our website visitors only based on our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

### **9\. Custom Services**

#### **Handling applicant data**

We offer website visitors the opportunity to submit job applications to us (e.g., via e-mail, via postal services on by submitting the online job application form). Below, we will brief you on the scope, purpose and use of the personal data collected from you in conjunction with the application process. We assure you that the collection, processing, and use of your data will occur in compliance with the applicable data privacy rights and all other statutory provisions and that your data will always be treated as strictly confidential.

#### **Scope and purpose of the collection of data**

If you submit a job application to us, we will process any affiliated personal data (e.g., contact and communications data, application documents, notes taken during job interviews, etc.), if they are required to make a decision concerning the establishment or an employment relationship. The legal grounds for the aforementioned are § 26 BDSG according to German Law (Negotiation of an Employment Relationship), Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR (General Contract Negotiations) and – provided you have given us your consent – Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR. You may revoke any consent given at any time. Within our company, your personal data will only be shared with individuals who are involved in the processing of your job application.

If your job application should result in your recruitment, the data you have submitted will be archived on the grounds of § 26 BDSG and Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR for the purpose of implementing the employment relationship in our data processing system.

#### **Data Archiving Period**

If we are unable to make you a job offer or you reject a job offer or withdraw your application, we reserve the right to retain the data you have submitted on the basis of our legitimate interests (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR) for up to 6 months from the end of the application procedure (rejection or withdrawal of the application). Afterwards the data will be deleted, and the physical application documents will be destroyed. The storage serves in particular as evidence in the event of a legal dispute. If it is evident that the data will be required after the expiry of the 6-month period (e.g., due to an impending or pending legal dispute), deletion will only take place when the purpose for further storage no longer applies.

Longer storage may also take place if you have given your agreement (Article 6(1)(a) GDPR) or if statutory data retention requirements preclude the deletion.

### **10\. Our social media presence**

#### **Data processing through social networks**

We maintain publicly accessible profiles on social networks. The social networks used by us in detail can be found below.

Social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, etc. can generally analyze your user behavior extensively when you visit their website or a website with integrated social media content (e.g., like buttons or advertising banners). Visiting our social media presences triggers numerous processing operations relevant to data protection. In detail:

If you are logged into your social media account and visit our social media presence, the operator of the social media portal can assign this visit to your user account. However, your personal data may also be collected under certain circumstances if you are not logged in or do not have an account with the respective social media portal. In this case, this data collection takes place, for example, via cookies that are stored on your end device or by recording your IP address.

With the help of the data collected in this way, the operators of the social media portals can create user profiles in which your preferences and interests are stored. In this way, interest-based advertising can be displayed to you inside and outside the respective social media presence. Provided you have an account with the respective social network, the interest-based advertising may be displayed on all devices on which you are or were logged in.

Please also note that we cannot track all processing on the social media portals. Depending on the provider, further processing operations may therefore be carried out by the operators of the social media portals. For details, please refer to the terms of use and data protection provisions of the respective social media portals.

#### **Legal basis**

Our social media presences are intended to ensure the most comprehensive presence possible on the Internet. This is a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The analysis processes initiated by the social networks may be based on deviating legal bases to be specified by the operators of the social networks (e.g. consent within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. a DSGVO).

#### **Responsible party and assertion of rights**

If you visit one of our social media sites (e.g. Facebook), we are jointly responsible with the operator of the social media platform for the data processing operations triggered during this visit. In principle, you can assert your rights (information, correction, deletion, restriction of processing, data portability and complaint) both vis-à-vis us and vis-à-vis the operator of the respective social media portal (e.g. vis-à-vis Facebook).

Please note that despite the joint responsibility with the social media portal operators, we do not have full influence on the data processing operations of the social media portals. Our options are largely determined by the corporate policy of the respective provider.

#### **Storage period**

The data collected directly by us via the social media presence is deleted from our systems as soon as the purpose for storing it no longer applies, you request us to delete it, revoke your consent to store it, or the purpose for storing the data no longer applies. Stored cookies remain on your terminal device until you delete them. Mandatory legal provisions - in particular retention periods - remain unaffected.

We have no influence on the storage period of your data, which is stored by the operators of social networks for their own purposes. For details, please contact the operators of the social networks directly (e.g. in their privacy policy, see below).

#### Social networks in detail

#### **Instagram**

We have a profile on Instagram. The provider is Instagram Inc, 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: https://www.facebook.com/legal/EU\_data\_transfer\_addendum, https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875 and https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381.

For details on their handling of your personal data, please refer to Instagram's privacy policy: https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875.

#### **TikTok**

We have a profile on TikTok. The provider is TikTok Technology Limited, 10 Earlsfort Terrace, Dublin, D02 T380, Ireland. For details on their handling of your personal data, please refer to TikTok's privacy policy: https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy?lang=de.

Data transfer to non-secure third countries is based on the EU Commission's standard contractual clauses. Details can be found here: https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy?lang=de.

#### **LinkedIn**

We have a profile on LinkedIn. The provider is LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. LinkedIn uses advertising cookies.

If you would like to disable LinkedIn advertising cookies, please use the following link: https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/l/dpa and https://www.linkedin.com/legal/l/eu-sccs.

For details on their handling of your personal data, please refer to LinkedIn's privacy policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy.

#### **YouTube**

We have a profile on YouTube. The provider is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. For details on how they handle your personal data, please refer to YouTube's privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de.

GAMMA Digital & Beyond is an innovation and transformation consultancy. We enable SMEs (a.k.a. “Mittelstand”) to accelerate, incubate and scale their innovation cycle and transformation process.

Enabling our clients to drive forward innovation themselves is our primary goal. This transformation is about changing the entire organization and mindset in order to remain adaptable to the ever ever-changing.

#### Navigation

#### General

©2025 GAMMA Digital & Beyond®

#014 – How Drug Cartels Operate & Innovate Like Silicon Valley Startups

Episode play icon

[#014 – How Drug Cartels Operate & Innovate Like Silicon Valley Startups](http://84ee9987efd14ba74908728c6ced42b7/)




